Jacob Beeson

Software Developer

Contact

Address

Austin, TX, 78724

Phone

(336) 486-3317

E-mail

boxnbeeson@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://tinyurl.com/JPBLIn

Portfolio

https://boxnbeeson.github.i o/CP/

Skills

React.is

Node.js

Express

JQuery

Inquirer

Handlebar.is

MySQL

MongoDB

Bootstrap

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Software developer with a MERN Full-Stack Certificate. Utilizes a bachelor's degree in psychology to enhance understanding of client's needs and improve teamwork in an agile environment. Experienced in front-end web design and back-end database/API connection. Further knowledge includes Bootstrap4, Handlebars.js, MySQL, noSQL, and more. Currently studying Python, C/C++, VIM, and Google Go.

Education

2021-07 -	Certificate In Full Stack Web Development
2021-08	The Hong Kong University of Science And Technology MERN and Bootstrap 4
2020-05 -	Certificate in Full Stack Web Development
2020-12	University Of North Carolina At Chapel Hill
	MERN (Mongo, Express, React, Node.js)
2013-08 -	Bachelor of Arts: Psychology
2019-08	University Of North Carolina At Chapel Hill

Projects

PROJECTS

<u>CoffeeHut</u> | https://tinyurl.com/CoffeeHutGH **Livelink:** https://tinyurl.com/CoffeeHutApp

- Summary: Web-based application where users may customize and order drinks from a local coffee shop
- Role: Front-end development
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, MySQL, Handlebars, Fontawesome

<u>React.js Portfolio</u> | https://tinyurl.com/RPortGH **Livelink:** https://tinyurl.com/ReactPGH

- Summary: Portfolio designed using React.js
- Role: Sole Developer
- Tools: React.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

<u>README Generator</u> | https://tinyurl.com/rmgGH

Tutorial: https://tinyurl.com/rmgtutorial

- Summary: CLI application that a client may use to easily create pre-formatted README.md files
- Role: Sole Developer
- Tools: JavaScript, inquirer, cli

Python

C/C++

Vim

Google Go

<u>Dinner Dice</u> | https://tinyurl.com/DinDiceGH

Livelink: https://tinyurl.com/DinDiceApp

- Summary: Entertainment application allowing users to try new dinner and drink recipes for date night
- Role: Back-end development
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, thecocktaildb/themealdb APIs

<u>Weather Dashboard</u> | https://tinyurl.com/WDashGH **Livelink:** https://tinyurl.com/WDashApp

- Summary: Weather application allowing users to search cities current broadcast and 5-day forecast
- Role: Sole Developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, API integration

Professional Experience & Community Involvement

2014-01 -2019-05 President, Assistant Coach, Vice-President, Head Trainer, Team Captain, Secretary

Carolina Boxing Club

- 2000+ hours of hands-on training with individuals and groups
- Instructed and supervised team of 10-15 trainers
- Provided daily updates and instructions to a club of 75-150 people
- Constructed daily boxing technique, conditioning, and training plans

2016-06 -2019-05

Security / Bartender

Pantana Bob's

- Fostered teamwork and leadership skills for a high-stress environment
- Developed the ability to defuse violent situations and resolve issues among patrons